[Music]
a
oh
[Music]
hello good evening good day everybody I
hope you're all doing very well and uh
welcome to this latest episode of the
ask abijit show as you know hopefully
that uh this is going to be a completely
uh live chat session in which I will
take questions only from the live chat
so that as many people as possible can
get the chance to ask me questions to
have me answer your questions and I get
and lots of more people can get exposure
to this so let's do this uh before
before we go into that into the
questions let me see who all is there on
the live chat let us see who all is in
attendance I can see Atul Pam Kang go
vinit another vinit vinit s bublu baban
kotaka kotaka Gil chandarana vikrant
marate Tas hello minini kushbu sures
Tanish Addie Beast gamer Zub eung Forum
kacha hello Nan Roshan maana Al
P amoga
udupa aush Pand Tushar Kori rushi shet
Om hello boria hello deos man Kiran
bandagi Kiran bandagi Sid sarar prech
aush
rdrr gaming lover arpit Kumar shubam
Kumar nabanita Das Tushar kalbur Chris
Rogers J geopolitics deos Das Gupta Anar
prian Su hello da Sharma nitin Jacob ji
Singh Namaste mes rushi Priyanka javala
r p p42 dianu rice Samana
Satish nandu uwala kadam Dr J Shankar
Namaste Vishnu mohanan kvsb Nani Som
Shar Joseph Stalin hello sir hello
hello Benzene Tas prian pranit
Aditya uh sh Sparkle Sky storm Amud
bavin alok Atul crazy brain hello the
everything Chagas and so on so forth I
will not be able to greet you all
individually but uh let me do a couple
more Mayan kitang harbon James pangam
even Tes Desai and so on all right all
right all right all right let's stop
this now uh hello to everybody hello to
all of you all of all of you who are
here and hopefully I can take your
questions so let's go for it please ask
your questions what questions do we have
what questions do we have let us go with
Sora borya in his book new harapan
discoveries in North Rajasthan and
Punjab Dr DP Sharma shows there there is
the presence of yagna with you stumb
which dates back to 2000 BC Vic okay
that's very interesting so yeah there is
this thing right there is this narrative
that the um the harapan the so-called
harapan phase of India's history was
so-called dravidian phase right and uh
so that's that's another way of claiming
that the Arians are foreigners and
Invaders and Arians exist I mean from my
perspective all Indians are Arya but
yeah so they they are they're trying to
continually bring in the Arian
Invasion migration tourism picnic myth
through the back door and yeah all that
so um okay I was not aware of this so in
this book Dr DP Sharma the author has
shown that there is a presence of yagi
with yup Thum which dates back to 2500
BC and according to the Arian Invasion
migration tourism picnic myth the Arians
did not come to India before 1500 BC so
this is a thousand years before that and
this is clearly Vic so once again one
more data point that blows a hole into
this Arian Invasion myth well thank you
for bringing this to our notice sorab
really appreciate
that P just says some historians claim
that chanaka was a mythical figure is
there any hard archaological evidence
that's a good question do we have an
see there's no hard archaeological
evidence of Alexander either
okay uh where's the hard archaeological
evidence for Julius Caesar okay fine we
have statues of Julius Caesar and we
have inscriptions and monuments
Alexander do we have anything so the
point is I'm not saying Alexander did
not exist my point is that there are
lots of historical figures for which we
don't have any hard archaeological
evidence it doesn't mean they did not
exist this uh I mean it's been passed on
from generation to generation in India
that there was a great man called Vishnu
chanakya and he was the mentor the the
guru of and the power behind the throne
in the in the uh beginning of the morian
Empire he was the guru of uh uh our
emperor chundra Gupta Moria and so on
and obviously he was a great Statesman
and much more and we have discovered the
book book that he wrote so obviously
when we go back 2 and a half thousand
years it's very hard to find hard
archaeological evidence for anything
that's why people claim that Lord Ram is
a myth and Lord Krishna is a myth and
Chandra Gupta vikramaditya is a myth and
everything is a myth in India only
eurocentric history is is is
true I mean so my point is it's clear
that he existed it's been the the
problem we face in India I've said this
so many times is that our libraries our
universities were destroyed universities
our libraries were burned libraries that
took months to burn imagine how much
information was stored in those
libraries everything was burned to ashes
so that's why if if we still had those
libraries even a couple of those even
just one of those even 10% of those we
would have way more information than we
have today and imagine how many records
of our history we lost in that so yeah
because of these things it's easy for
people to claim that these are myths but
clearly these are not myths so that's
the point yeah I I take your point
completely do we have hard
archaeological evidence of the existence
of V Vish chanakya archaeological
evidence we don't have it we don't have
archaeological evidence of Chandra Gupta
Mori either we have buildings we have
old patle Putra but does it mean Chandra
Gupta Moria lived there I mean do we
have inscriptions that attest to Chandra
Gupta morya as far as I know we don't we
have inscriptions of Ashok but even in
asok it says padash priyashi many of
these inscriptions don't even name
Emperor ashoke by name they don't
mention him by name so shall we say that
Emperor ashoke also was a myth so
because of so the convergence of so many
data points and all that that's why we
can we can um understand that these
people actually existed now the question
is when did they exist that's also a
good question and I'm sure that India's
histor India's historical chronography
needs to be Revisited because there
there have been so many there have been
multiple uh Chandra guptas in India and
there have been multiple viadas as well
so which is which it's entirely possible
that the morian Chandra Gupta Chandra
Gupta of the first of the Moran Dynasty
may have existed a thousand years before
we believe it was and maybe it was a
different Chandra Gupta that the Greeks
called Sandra kotos that's also possible
so there is so much in India's history
that is all up in the air it's all much
of it is based on various assumptions
but one assumption but but the claim
that many of these his historical
figures were
that's what I don't agree about I would
definitely be open to revisiting the
chronology the chronology of the Buddha
the chronology of mahavir the chronology
of the Moran Empire and so on and I have
this podcast on my on this channel uh
with Mr V Arya who has put forth an
alternate a different histo different
chronology of India's history and much
of it much of what he says makes a lot
of sense so I would invite you all to I
would encourage you all to check it out
okay all
right Atul says my views on Mike Tyson
versus Jake Paul
oh I look my favorite boxer I mean I
haven't lived in the era of Muhammad Ali
and all that people who were alive in
the 1960s ET they they claimed that he
was the best the greatest of all time
from my perspective from my lifespan
what I've seen there's no one like M
Mike Tyson okay the greatest I've seen
the most devastating brutal boxer I've
ever seen nobody could withstand himand
him what how tall was he 510 I'm I'm
sure he was less than 6 feet tall and he
would devastate guys is like six and a
half feet tall and all that so the
greatest of all time from my perspect
perspective from what I have seen with
my eyes on TV obviously not in not in
real life so that's Mike Tyson but he's
in his 50s today we have to be realistic
Jake Paul is what 20 20 something 27 26
whatever I don't think Mike Tyson is
going to do well he was the greatest
when he was young he was a beast nobody
could withstand what he Unleashed but in
his 50s come on I I I don't see Mike
Tyson winning I hope I'm wrong I would
be the happiest person to see Mike Tyson
defeat Jake Paul I have nothing against
Jake Paul either my point is Mike Tyson
is in his 50s Jake Paul is in his
20s uh Jake Paul is a professional boxer
by the way you can't dismiss his
abilities and whatever he's achieved
thus far so I think it's going to be
tough for Mike Tyson okay I I hope I'm
wrong but from a realistic perspective
uh I think it's going to be tough for
Mike Tyson to defeat Jake Paul I mean I
remember I was I'm a huge fan of I don't
know if you people know him Fedor
emilianenko The Last Emperor MMA the
Russian guy he's another guy who was not
a huge tall six and a half feet tall guy
he's just six feet tall okay I'm a huge
fan of that guy I believe he's the
greatest of all time when it comes to
MMA mixed martial arts Fedor Emon enko
but in his last few fights that I saw it
was so disappointing to see how he was
beaten up by guys who were like 10 years
younger than him okay so that's just
these are just Facts of Life as you grow
older you can't do what you could do
when you were in your 20s Fedor was in
his early 40s when he was beaten up by a
guy in his early 30s what was that guy's
name I forget the guy's name that guy
doesn't even matter but he was he was no
great fighter but that's what happened
uh so I think it's going to be hard for
Mike Tyson to uh defeat Jake Paul
obviously I hope I'm wrong but yeah
that's how I see
it Prashant Sharma says what's your
opinion on the all eyes on Rafa Moto is
Israel putting it too far or is it
reasonable in their P from their
perspective listen this is not my fight
this is not India's fight it is a fight
between two two foreign Nations and let
them fight it out doesn't affect
me okay I I am not a stakeholder my
country our my people are not
stakeholders in this okay so if Israel
is fighting someone and that somebody is
fighting Israel it's their fight it's
not of my business it's none of none of
our business now my point
is I know I'm aware that most people in
India uh are favorably inclined towards
towards Israel for a variety of reasons
I'll not go into the reasons okay and
there's a there's a certain segment of
Indian population that is very strongly
Pro Gaza and Hamas and whatever else
Palestinians and very strongly anti
Israel okay and I'm sure there is there
are divisions on religious lines and all
that but the majority of Indians are
pro-israel my point is you can like a
nation you can admire a nation for
whatever reason but you don't put any
flag on your picture Pro on your profile
except for your country's flag and I
find it really annoying when people put
up flags of some other Nation whichever
it is the only flag on your profile
should be your your flag and right now
the Indian flag is the tricolor in the
future it may be a different flag that's
fine that's fine but right now it's the
Indian tricolor and if you want to put a
flag on your profile it should be your
country's flag not somebody else's
flag now so my point is that
I don't have a dog in this fight I don't
have a horse in this
race and I find it really curious that
there are certain Indians who today
today have been pushing this all eyes on
Rafa
propaganda it may be right it may be
wrong I don't care it's not my fight it
doesn't concern me it doesn't concern my
country it doesn't concern my people so
why does it concern certain Indians and
why do they have to put it up aren't
there enough problems in
India don't you have any sympathy for
the people uh for the displaced people
of Kashmir who have been displaced for
decades don't you have any sympathy for
the people in Manipur who have been
displaced by
foreigners but you have sympathy for for
some some people with whom you have no
connection no
relation 2,000 kilometers away what the
hell is this and the point the problem
is I have listen if if you belong to a
certain religion and if you find some
Affinity with them that's fine I
understand that it's okay it's your
choice
maybe you you have
more Affinity loyalty to some other
place than your country fine okay maybe
there also we can understand my problem
is there are people who are paid to post
this on social media soall
influencers
okay so that is my problem and these
many of these people pretend to be what
Pro India Pro indic Wing or whatever
else and these are the people who are
posting this all eyes on Raa thing some
people I personally know also by the way
okay so yeah interesting to see this and
I'll tell you
what if there are certain Pro India Pro
indic Wing Pro whatever Wing people who
have posted this you can never trust
them again okay don't forget don't
forget these things don't forget these
things I'm not asking you to take any
action whatsoever I'm just telling you
don't trust them again they can be
bought with money that's all I'll say
about this it's okay to take money
sponsorships or whatever but you
don't there are certain things you don't
do and the problem with this all eyes
and Raa thing is that the same people
who push this narrative are the people
who will push the pro Pakistani Kashmir
narrative that is the problem I have
otherwise I don't care if it doesn't
concern India if it doesn't harm India I
don't care but the same people who push
the Palestinian
propaganda narrative the same people who
pushed this Rafa and Hamas Pro Hamas Pro
Rafa anti-israel narrative they are the
same people the same lobbies in the US
who push the pro Pakistani anti-india BR
khalistani Kashmir propaganda Etc that's
my problem and they are the ones who are
the source of the funding to these indiv
the so-called influencers who have been
posting this today so that's why I say
this those who who who pretend to be on
on your side on India's side you know
nationalists and pro indic wing and
whatever and then they go ahead and post
this you can never trust them again so
make a note of the people who have done
this I'm not asking you to take any
action whatsoever just remember that
these
people can be bought with money and they
don't care who's paying the money as
long as they get
it yeah there you have it sir
okay V man says would what would Shri
chanakya if you were alive today teach
me to be a great leader look look I
don't know you personally so so don't
take it personally at all I don't know
you right and Sh chanaka also doesn't
know you my point is he would not teach
the great secrets to any any
anybody such the real lessons of
leadership the secrets of leadership
aren't meant for everybody they are
meant only for those who have those
qualities and who really deserve it and
it's not enough to be to have qualities
great qualities you need to have the the
will
power and the willingness to put in
everything it takes very few people have
that there are lots of people who are
born with
Talent lots of people who are born with
tremendous talent and most of the time
the tremendous Talent the gift of the
Gods goes waste because those people are
lazy and they simply can't take the pain
of hard
work so my point is Shri vishnugupta
chanakya would look at people very very
carefully he had the eye for that and he
would teach these secrets to maybe one
out of a
billion okay what was the population of
India the Moran era maybe 5 10 million
50 million I don't know whatever so one
out of that okay he did not teach that
lightly to to like 27 different people
he taught it only to one person and that
person he mentored for the for for the
rest of his life and of course control
that person I
mean Chandra Gupta was under tight
control by the way and that was see
chanaka did not serve his Emperor
chanaka
served
bhat so uh well there are lots of
Secrets when it comes to leadership it's
not really secret it's all out there in
the open you you any great leader and
you follow their patterns you will also
do the same things but there are certain
things mentally and all which would be
Secrets which probably I'm also not
aware of so so I don't know those
Secrets myself you
see I know it's not the answer you
wanted but you're got to be
truthful suit statement says do you
think India should invade its neighbors
to make a greater India and what do we
gain by doing doing that right now tell
me we gain territory but we gain those
populations do you want those
populations coming into your country do
you want that
those deeply
radicalized people Millions hundreds of
millions of them who want you
dead what will you do with them greater
India will happen when it happens it's
going to take time it's going to take
decades maybe a couple of centuries
perhaps okay invading and defeating your
neighbors is no big deal but taking that
land the land doesn't come alone it's
it's a package deal it comes with the
people right so I don't think India
should do that right now and we don't
want any War right now next 20 years we
don't want war we want to grow the
economy India's economy is growing we
want it to keep growing because once it
is it keeps grow growing for 20 years
straight then imagine the kind of muscle
power India will have military muscle
power then things will happen without
you having to do anything so no we don't
do this right now we mind our business
we work hard these are like you
know so it's like a cricket match and
you have 300 runs to score and you can
keep scoring one run a ball but
sometimes bats you know batsman can't
take the pressure of keep of keep of
consistently doing that so they try and
hit a six and they get out don't do that
you to be be in this for for the Long
Haul long
run um
the just says why did the sasan and
Gupta empires not work together when
thorana invaded India did the Gupta
Empire not interact with Kings outside
India at the time when the AL alhan
alhan hun invaded look the sassanids the
sasanians were our neighbors Persia
across the well across present day
baluchistan okay our neighbors Persians
our cousins and we have we had the Gupta
Empire which was this massive Empire
okay tremendously powerful Empire
Kumar Gupta had taken bik bul present
day bul and all that uh tremendously
powerful Empire but then you have the
old Emperor kumaragupta who's elderly
and he has this young son whose name was
uh skandagupta was it yeah yes scand
Gupta so this young man who is the the
the Crown Prince
yuvaraj and the father is old Kumar
Gupta and these these hordes of no start
pouring into India they triy to start
pouring into India and at the the time
they were invading India they were
trying to invade India same time they
were invading Rome the same people the
Huns and we're talking about the Sha
hunas here the white Huns okay the the
hepit the alhan Huns are a different
bunch of H All honic Peoples all speak
spoke the same language similar language
similar culture similar lifestyle
nomadic lifestyle and all but the alakar
Huns were different from the Sha
hunas so uh
I imagine did we have the Sans in power
in in Persia at the time let's let's I
don't remember right now okay but let's
assume the Sans were in power well from
their perspective it was not their
problem I don't think the Huns were
invading Persia at the time they were
they were after India India this
gigantic place with so much wealth they
wanted that so uh so scand Gupta has to
fight the Huns his father is old he
cannot lead the Army anymore more
elderly man so the emperor will stay at
home and the yaj goes and fights the HS
and he and he repels wave after wave
after wave of hunnik
invasion and he spent his whole life
doing that his father passed away
eventually and then he was the emperor
of India and he spent his entire life
repulsing the Huns it devastated his
economy his treasury everything was
spent in the defense of bhat
and that is the that was the cause of
the decline and eventual demise of the
Gupta Empire
now why did the sasanians not come to
India's help it was not their problem
they were the Huns were not invading
them at the time as far as I
remember and obviously you would have
some differences I mean it's a
neighboring country you don't trust the
look they may be your cousins they may
be your brothers but when they when you
are neighbors and you have two different
political Powers there's going to be
friction when India was unified under a
single Empire at multiple points in it
history like the Moran Empire kusan
empire Gupta Empire and so on at that
time everything was fine but when India
was
fragmented okay let's say after the
Gupta Empire or before the Gupta Empire
we we had a fragmentation of of the
country after the demise of the shunga
Empire the successor of Kingdom the
successor Empire of the morian empire
was a shunga Empire which lasted barely
a century and then you had all these
different Kingdoms in India you think
they were they were on friendly terms no
they also had the same thing so if
somebody were to invade one of the
kingdoms the other would be yeah yeah
yeah good chance for me I will then take
advantage of what happens what whatever
Misfortune bef befalls this this
neighbor of mine so that's how it goes
that's how it goes and that's
unfortunately how it is so for a country
to be safe and all that you need to be
politically United especially in a
civilization like India you need that
that doesn't happen
often uh did the Gupta Empire not
interact with Kings outside India when
the alakar Hun
invaded uh look I'm sure there were
relations and all that but we've lost
all the evidence of that we've lost all
the evidence all the universities
libraries were destroyed and whatever
records we may have had of these
interactions letters Communications
dispatches all that it's all gone so I'm
sure it was there of course it was there
but we don't have the records anymore
for for example when it comes to our
emperor Ashok he was aware of rulers of
Egypt when Ashok was in power in
patliputra presiding over the entire
subcontinent at that time it was I
believe toi the first or toi II who was
in in power in in Egypt so when
Alexander the Greek invaded or just
walked into Egypt he put a govern in
power in Egypt and that was T and then
after the demise very rapid demise of
Alexander then T became the king of
Egypt you know and that was the Greek
phase of Egyptian history and as we know
Cleopatra kopara was was Greek she was
not uh Egyptian she was Greek uh so so
so on so forth so so Ashok knew who was
in power in uh Egypt he even has
inscriptions that mention the names of
various Kings far far away from India so
I am sure there were connections there
were relationships and all I mean India
was trading with Rome the Romans were
sending us to mless amounts of gold in
exchange for spices we had relations and
connections everywhere but we have lost
those records that's the
problem
okay Shar Chri says do you think the two
sides of Bengal will reunite eventually
one day it will which which by what
means will it happen remains to be seen
the Bengali people are one people of
course we know what's happened in the
past few centuries in Bengal which has
caused this Division and right now it is
being unified through through osmosis it
looks like you know the poorest
borders and our our neighboring Bengali
are just pouring into India into bhat
the number that's put out reliably by
high placed sources is at least 50
million of them in India and then you
have the ringas from arakan
uh well that's a different issue that's
not the question I understand yeah
eventually the whole of the subcontinent
will re reunite but when will it happen
we don't know we don't want it to happen
right now because that will be a problem
given the cultural inclinations
religious inclinations of people I mean
the lands we have lost starting from
gandhar uh but eventually it will happen
at some point in time I will I think so
for I'm pretty sure it
will uh
Shanay Verma says what do you think
about Pakistan's statement of admitting
their fault in the Cargill War also what
do you think about the recent
developments in the Rafal deal between
India and France I am not aware of the
Rafal deal recent developments but Kil
War I think n Sharif made some statement
about something or other what what
difference what difference do it make
words what's the difference between
words and actions it's the difference is
infinity you know you can keep on
shooting people and then you you can
keep saying sorry after blowing
someone's head off so I admit my fault I
was wrong but what then what what what
difference does that make admitting your
fault so I think nothing of it it is
meaningless it is irrelevant okay
whatever admission of fault they've done
if you the only thing that would be
meaningful is Pakistan dismantling the
terror factories and handing over all
the wanted terrorists to India and
bringing all the other terrorists on
their soil to Justice
essentially locking them up forever that
would be the only thing that makes any
sense that's that's the only thing that
actually is Meaningful apart from that
any statements I don't care okay recent
developments in the Rafal deal between
India and
France not aware of what recent deal may
have happened recent development may
have happened does India want 36 more 72
more I'm sure we can buy more we could
even set up a production line in IND in
India if we if we have a sufficiently
large order what I'm really interested
in is uh
technology not Rafal technology jet
engine technology because I don't want
the Rafal I want jet engine technology
and as we know we have been trying to
develop a whatever engines for a very
long time not sure what the issue is
whether it's a lack of funding whether
it's a lack of
uh uh
whatever but yeah let's let's be smart
and buy the technology right and and the
the thing about about jet engines is
that it's very very Niche
technology jet engines especially jet
engines in fighter planes you know
supersonic jet jet engines that can
produce supersonic thrust that can that
have a Thrust to weight ratio when it
comes to the entire aircraft of plus of
of more than one which means it thrust
is more than the weight of the of the of
the plane when you have engines like
that for military applications those
engines the in those engines the fuel
Burns at incredibly high temperatures I
don't know 2,000 3,000 degrees Celsius
something like that high enough to to
melt steel so then how do you operate
such engines what do you make them off
turbine blades the turbine blades are at
the heart of the matter they are the
ones that you know are at the heart of
the engine will they not melt so what
needs to happen what the solution to
this is to build every single turbine
blade out of a single Crystal of metal
the entire blade is a single Crystal and
then it has certain properties that are
that make it extremely re heat resistant
now to develop this technology takes
decades so just buy it that's my
point uh so if you look at the history
of jet engine development it's something
you a company or a nation invests in for
decades and it iteratively improves the
technology so we don't want to spend
another five decades developing jet
engine technology we just want it now so
I hear that we have two deals I hear
okay I I hear I've heard this I've not
actually read it not actually seen it
I've heard this that we may have two
deals going on one with the French with
saf or snma or I think and the other one
could be with the rash our rashan
friends could be giving us some
technology for money of course yes so
yeah just get the get the technology pay
whatever it takes not too much not pay
but get the technology that's that's all
all right all
right um let's see some other
questions nikit mger says how do us
elections affect all ongoing Wars us
elections make no difference in Wars the
US war machine is entirely separate from
its apparently Democratic uh nature
whatever the Democratic process okay so
uh uh the US elections will not affect
any wars whether it's Mr Biden who comes
back to Power whether it is Miss Kamala
Harris who becomes the next prime
president whether it is Mr Trump who
becomes president it really won't make
any much of a
difference first of all I don't see Mr
Trump becoming president they don't they
won't allow him to become
president we know what they did in the
2020 election huh we know what happened
in that election
so same thing will happen at even in a
even better way in the 20 before
election I don't see Trump coming back
to power but it doesn't really matter US
foreign policy never changes no matter
who is the president of the
US crazy brain says do atoms have a
lifespan well it depends it depends
first of all let's go deeper from then
the atom let's go to subatomic particles
like protons neutrons electrons so we
have proton decay protons do Decay but
when when they're in a bound State
inside nucleus they don't decay for some
reason so even protons have a lifespan
or half life let's say okay but when
they are bound inside a nucleus they
don't Decay for some
reason I'll just keep it at that okay so
first of all you have that
electrons maybe there's only one
electron in the universe that's also a
possibility going backwards and forwards
in
time uh that's also a possibility so
okay we'll talk about atoms now yeah
atoms so some atoms have a lifespan it's
called a halflife and a halflife
pertains to radioactive elements
radioactivity is the process through
which atoms of one element transmute
into atoms of a different element we
have spoken about Thorium we've talk
spoken about uranium Etc there is
plutonium there is
polonium then
radium various kinds of elements that
are radioactive elements and they come
in various
Isotopes and those atoms are typically
so large that they that the
uh atoms the the the nuclei are kind of
unstable you go beyond a certain number
the nuclei kind of in some cases become
unstable uh so uranium is a great
example it's an unstable atom and it
eventually transmutes into a different
element uh so yeah so a specific atom if
you show me one atom and ask me to
predict its lifespan I cannot you give
me a kilogram of uranium I can tell you
what its half life will be so I can tell
you that in so much time half of the
these atoms will transmute into
something else that's what I can tell
you statistically it's a stat
statistical thing but a single atom I
can't say that's the weirdness of
quantum physics of the quantum world so
yeah but when it comes to hydrogen Etc
well it doesn't really have a lifespan I
think it can exist forever unless it's
within a star in which case it will
undergo
fusion and it will be the the the fuel
that that powers the
star and yeah so yeah when you have
Fusion inside Stars hydrogen atoms get
converted into various other helium
atoms and so on because of the extreme
pressure incredi incredible
gravitational pressure uh the force that
is exerted by the sheer mass of the star
and there's this tag of war going on
between the implosion and the explosion
and that's why stars have a certain size
until they don't until they start
forming iron at the core in which time
in which case they their lifespan is
then measured in
milliseconds and then you know what
happens yes is
Supernova
okay okay what is this question godov
says what general do
you cassette futurism like 2001 Space
Odyssey or more of a s Hightech sci-fi
you like any Alfred Hitchcock movies as
a kid I saw a few Alfred Hitchcock
movies uh what was it vertigo was it
vertigo was a great movie dial M for
Murder uh who was that lady in that uh
my fair lady what's her name I forget
the lady's
name yeah my fair lady the the the the
the principal actress in that
movie no I forget the name anyway I've
seen a couple of Alfred H hcock movies
good movies uh I like science fiction
movies yes 2001 Space Audy was a good
movie high-tech sci-fi I don't mind
Hightech sci-fi I don't mind dystopian
sci-fi sometimes Event Horizon was a
great movie Lawrence Fishburn was in
their Event Horizon recent of recent in
recent times you had uh what's it
called Dune Dune was a greatly was a
great movie in the sense that the the
the cinematography was in incredibly
beautiful but one character just I
couldn't stand there was
chani there has to be at least one
feminist character right that ruins the
whole movie yeah the alpha
nag we have what this this thing called
alpha males right so in in this in this
movie there was the alpha nag who even
out nags the mother
anyhow so dun was okay that that one
character just ruined it for me and then
uh Interstellar was great and so on so I
could go on about this but yeah I like
I'm I'm a big movie buff but these days
you don't get to see good movies too
many good
movies
okay okay Tanish Kumar says man's body
frozen at-200 Dees celi in hope to bring
him back to life in the future in
Australia is it even possible
sir I think it's very hard to if you
freeze someone to minus 200 Celsius
I don't see
it feasible to bring that person back to
life let me explain why let me explain
why I don't think it's possible look we
are what 70% water 7 whatever percent uh
I think when a human being is an infant
it's about 70 something per water when
you are in your 50s you're about 60%
water when you're in your 70s you're
about 50% water so it
depends but let's say you are 70% or
let's say you just 50% water
so all your
organs they have liquid inside right
blood but blood is mostly water isn't it
now do you know what happens when water
goes to 0 degrees cius it freezes we
know that it becomes ice but have you
seen the microscopic structure of ice
crystals they are they have sharp
edges razor sharp edges and and needle
like shapes look at snow just just
Google snow right
snowflakes snowflakes are fragile but
when you go to because they start
melting that's why they're fragile and
they're so small but when you have a
solid frozen mass of blood and all of
that liquid is in the form of ice
crystals can you imagine what it will do
to your the internal structure of your
body what it will do to organs what it
will do to your cells because inside a
cell you have water
mostly what will it do to the
mitochondria what will it do to the
golgy bodies what will it do to the
endoplasmic reticulum what will it do to
the cell membrane cell wall it'll
puncture all that what will it do to
your neurons it'll ruin your neurons so
you freeze somebody it will just you
will have microscopic trauma that will
that you can never rep you know uh
recuperate
from so I don't unless you first drain
all the blood out but then the then how
do you revive the person so I don't see
this possible right now at this point in
time that this sort of thing so you
freeze somebody in the hope that in in
500 years time uh we will have the
technology to do this but in 500 years
time it'll be a different technology
freezing one work so yeah so I don't
know why people are so obsessed with
being alive forever and all that stuff
what's the
point
okay next question
what happened is here yeah Anita says in
Pompei the Romans wore red for their
weddings they put put food on an altar
in their home for the gods and prayed to
them before eating the food I think the
Romans were
Hindus look all polytheistic cultures
are very much the same then the Romans
were an Indo-European culture which is
the oldest Indo-European religious text
it is the
Riga which is the oldest Indo European
language is a Sanskrit
right and the gods they woried I mean
who the greatest of their gods it is
Jupiter yes the Roman god Jupiter the
greatest of their gods the the king of
their
Pantheon so
Jupiter was the Roman version of Zeus
Peter Zeus the Greek god Zeus Peter okay
and the Greek God Zeus Peter was the
Greek version of Dios P the Vic God that
no one remembers today the father of all
the gods the father of
Indra and of course Zeus Peter has
elements of D petu and also has elements
of Indra himself because he has the
Thunderbolt right the vajra and Zeus
Zeus defeats tyon which is a great sea
serpent sea monster which is their
version of the Ric vitra so it is the
same thing the Roman were worshipping
the same gods in different names and in
different ways so you are right it is a
good observation in their Customs they
had the swastika look at their their
mosaics you find in Pompei and other
places North Africa wherever else look
at the Mosaic decorations they have
swastikas everywhere they even had
swastika
lamps so yes the similarities are too
too numerous and too widespread to be
ignored
but yes if you say this that they were
Hindus that people get upset no no no
they were
Romans PR PR amales says how would India
deal with the twoof front war against
Pakistan and China in the near future
well we don't know if it's in the near
future but a hypothetical war in a
future scenario let's say a near future
scenario let's say next weekend the
Chinese and Pakistan say okay let's
invade India together what do we do so
when you have you're fighting a twoof
front War hm you want to end one front
immediately so India will have to find a
way to end the Pakistani front of the
war in about 5 to 15 minutes and I'm not
talking about using nuclear weapons we
have other ways of doing it so we have
to launch in the case of a twoof front
war with Pakistan and China at the same
time when both these nations
simultaneously attack India if that
hypothetical scenario happens India has
to immediately neutralize Pakistan once
and for all inflict a blow that they can
not recover from that's the first thing
I have no hatred or anything against the
people people of Pakistan this is just
I'm just telling you logic logically
what should happen the the Chinese are a
whole different Beast so we have to
first deal with Pakistan immediately
neutralize the Pakistani threat within 5
to 15 minutes and I'm not talking about
using nuclear weapons Just Launch a
devastating coordinated series of
strikes in Pakistan and end that threat
Pakistan is it's not hard to deal with
it's it's a thin Nation thin
geographically thin sliver of land
everything is within reach for India
missiles fighter planes
whatever wipe out their ports wipe out
their their
ships make sure the submarines have no
place to go to if they're out in on
patrol and take out the runways their
fighter planes and take out the nuclear
facilities or whatever I'll not go into
specific details but neutralize the
threat of Pakistan in 15 minutes 5 to 15
minutes then then you can deal with
China differently so the Chinese
presence okay I have not opened the map
today is incredible is not acceptable we
must have map so where is map we see map
yes is here okay so let's take a look at
the Chinese presence in occupied
Tibet so you can see this network of
roads all over the place in China yes
and we have a similar kind of network in
India roads everywhere now look at
Chinese occupied Tibet how many roads do
they have hardly any there's only one or
two roads that supply that that connect
Tibet to mainland
China so you take out the roads you take
out the supply chains you you take out
the all the connectivity and you you hit
their airports and everything hard and
then you do if if you take you know you
effect a blitz Greek strategy in which
you send your your personnel in a
variety of ways into Tibet and you and
you capture parts of Tibet that's what
you do and then you hold on to them so
what needs to happen is that India
cannot fight defensive war against
China that that won't work you have to
take the fight to Chinese occupied
territory you know
what uh one of my podcast guests a
couple of years ago was Dr Edward Luwak
one of the greatest geost strategists in
in the world okay he has advised
governments Prime Ministers and
presidents he was on my podcast you know
what he
said you know what it what it takes to
conquer
China it takes three guys on Horseback
that's what it takes to conquer China
the point he was trying to make Dr
lutwak is that China has never succeeded
succeeded in fighting a defensive War
when you take the war to their territory
they always
lose so India if if there's a war with
China once you've dealt with the
Pakistan issue you can't fight a
defensive war war against China you have
to take the fight on Tibetan territory
you take out the supply chains you take
out the communication uh lines the road
the railways you take out the airports
and you go and capture territory
physically you go into
Lassa ideally you go to urumi and so on
I mean yeah you've got to develop the
capability do to do that so that's what
needs to happen you go into the
territory you capture cities you capture
big parts of territory and you hold on
to that and you make them negot for that
not for Indian Land that's what needs to
happen
yes cost jwal says have you watched a
Death Note I think I've watched one or
two episodes long long ago there is a
there is a creature called a Shinigami
right
Shinigami and there's this book and
stuff like that and then who's the guy
Kira Kira so I've seen a couple of
episodes but I yeah couldn't finish it
there's so so much I've not watched but
I'm aware of Death Note I hear it's a
one of the legendary anime shows or
yeah
[Music]
okay uh okay anupam Jen says why is the
CIA interfering now so openly and why
are we
doing and are we doing anything about it
I think is I think the CIA propaganda
anti- Modi views even by creating hline
Hindu speakers Etc there are lots of
people who are
available I'm not naming anybody okay
I'm just saying generally people are
available for higher if the price is if
the price is right everybody apparently
has a price that's what I see not
everybody some people don't have a price
but many people do so it's not so hard
to have people that are on your payroll
whether it is some private university
somewhere in some part of India
prestigious hypothetical University edly
and you you are some Professor who gets
invitations to to lecture in the
US okay and you you get to write
articles op EDS in us or or Indian
Publications so you are uh prestigious
you you are a person of prestige and
Status yeah and then you push Pro us
anti-india anti-russia propaganda
allegedly I'm I'm talking about a
hypothetical scenario here I'm not
naming anybody just hypothetically there
could be such people and there could be
such hypothetical private universities
and there could be other people also not
in universities but let's say somewhere
else influencers allegedly
hypothetically or so on or so so forth
it's easy to buy such people it's easy
to easy to purchase their allegiance and
their services without sometimes them
not even know knowing who is paying for
this and what what they are being asked
to do the people are most people aren't
the brightest you see most people cannot
connect the
dots oh but I was just paid for
collaboration I did collaboration it is
harmless that's s of stuff um but yes so
the C I'm not I don't know if it's a CIA
or the Deep State or the FBI or the US
government Department of State whatever
it's the US okay from my perspective
from sitting here it's the US I'm not
going to speculate whether it's a CIA or
the Pentagon or the Department of
Defense or the department of whatever or
the department of of black magic or
Department of whatever it doesn't matter
it's the US they are doing this now what
they do they they're pretty sure
everyone's pretty sure that Mr Modi is
indeed coming back to Power in a week's
time the once the election results are
declared I hope so I very much want him
to come back with a large majority of
course no secret here so uh even they
are pretty much sure that it's going to
happen so they are setting the stage to
attack India and to attack the Modi
government and to attack Mr Modi
personally by creating this entire
narrative all kinds of narratives about
India India's democracy is backsliding
India is becoming an authoritarian State
India is a dictatorship according to
certain influencers and so on do you
know what a dictatorship is like okay
I've already spoken about this before so
anyhow I think what they're trying to do
is they're trying to set the stage for
the next five years of attacking India
and that's why they're creating this
these narratives right now okay um
think ask and learn please please
recommend the best books and movies
related to a historical power struggle
how politics Works in power structure
Etc the Earth sh the prince Art of War
Etc The Art of War is a book of
strategems it's not a book of strategy
it's a book of
strats Google the
difference I not and just you can
consult your favorite dictionary to
understand the difference between a
strategy and strategy The Art of War by
tunu is the book of strates the prince
is by Nicola makavelli and that's
supposed to be the Great Book of
strategy and realism and all that well
that's nothing it pales in comparison to
the AR shastra which is a whole
different
level uh best books in movies
movies you don't learn much from
movies watch watch HBO's room HBO's room
that's good that's all about politics in
power struggles and it's about the rise
and fall of Julius Kaiser and Mark
Anthony and um Augustus and so
on I saw that many many years ago it was
a good I think it's a two season thing
so there is that room it's boo then if
you want to learn about power struggle
and politics watch House of
Cards
uh it's it's interesting as long as this
guy is there on screen Frank
Underwood Kevin spacy then what else
what else Game of Thrones is all about
the brutality of of west of the western
society and overall human nature and all
that
and books look I don't I I can make a
list of books if I spend half a day and
think about it and revisit everything
I've read but right now if you ask me on
the spot I won't be able to remember any
book because I've read so many you know
I don't remember who quote this says but
it applies to me I've had thousands of
meals in my life I don't remember them
on them all I've had thousands of meals
in my life I remember none of them but
they made me who I am and similarly I've
read thousands of books in my life I
don't remember most of them but they
also made me who I am so that's how it
is uh I could put out a list in the
future but right now I can't think of
books because I've read so many it all
merges in your mind in my
mind
okay all right what okay let's go to
preek preek says I took je Mains SL
Advanced I love engineering physics but
found that most IIT grads end up in
coding coming from a lower middle class
family I need stability but dislike
coding well Welcome to the Real World
sir you have to be practical in
life what you love and what
you what really motivates you and what
you're passionate about may not always
be the thing that pays the
bills so what you can do see you are
from a lower mid lower middle class
family you obviously need to uh earn
money good money for a for a sustained
period of time so
there's there's no you know there's no
way
that you're going to be able to make a
lot of money if you are a if you are a
college teacher Pro Professor or
whatever if you are a university
Professor you will have a stable job and
maybe a decently good salary one lakh
1.5 lakhs depending on where you go but
uh to be very realistic very few people
get those jobs right so I think you have
to be practical and realistic and maybe
do coding for a decade or so I mean you
don't always get to do what you love
eventually you may get into what you
love but you sometimes have to pay your
dues I worked in it for a decade
personally you think I enjoyed that you
got to do it if you got to do it so yeah
that's all I can say be practical be
realistic and you're still very young in
a decades time you'll still be very
young okay so and you'll learn a lot not
just about fooding and all that but
about
life so do what it takes to succeed
first and then enjoy your
life
okay Liberal
mongr Liberal Mongrel says don't you
think there should be a common syllabus
for same subjects like chemistry physics
at graduation level in the entirety of
India as we have to refer to multiple
multiple books which is kind of headache
I completely agree with you there should
be standardization and uniformity when
it comes to the scient science subjects
chemistry is chemistry everywhere why do
you need 17 different
thei in 17 different universities and
colleges everybody has their own
syllabus it's not like they're
Reinventing something right when it
comes to physics physics is physics you
just need one book at the high school in
college level this one H day
rnic whichever Edition that is I think
it's the fourth edition Edition I
thought it was sixth but it's Fourth
today you have the 78th Edition I'm sure
of holiday and
rnck there's a guy called Walker also in
the mix now anyway my point is there
should be standardization there should
be uniformity especially in the
scientific subjects the the disciplines
of science mathematics science
mathematics physics chemistry why can't
you standardize the syllabus across the
country in the same
textbooks recommend the best textbooks
right not some Third Rate trashy author
who doesn't even know how to write I've
seen plenty of those I won't name them
because it will embarrass them but there
are so many trashy books when it comes
to
physics third grade books I don't know
why people bother to write that just
because they want to be called an author
right that's why there's only a few
books you need to
read and uh yeah so my point is I
completely agree with you I don't
understand why we have this nonsense in
India it just makes life so difficult
for the true stakeholder
who is the
student parikshit J says have you
watched Oppenheimer if yes what did you
think of it I have watched
it it's not often that they put out a a
movie about a physicist so I thought
I'll watch it it was a good movie it's
not the kind of movie that I would be
motivated to watch more than once it was
a good movie the guy uh uh what's his
name
Killian kilan Murphy I think his name is
uh I think he did a great job great
acting um it was it was not really about
physics it was about politics mostly it
was about the Witch Hunt that he had to
go through mostly Oppenheimer and
there's some nice shots of the first the
the Trinity Atomic test and all that so
I think
my my the way I see it is it was a good
movie but not a great movie not the kind
of movie I want to go and watch again
you know I heard that Interstellar is
going to come back in theaters later
this year I don't know September October
November somewhere then I'm going to go
and watch it again in the theater that's
a movie I don't mind watching three
times four times Oppenheimer doesn't
motivate me to do that if they put out
if they put Star Wars back on the screen
big screens I'll go and watch it if they
put the lot of lot of the Rings trilogy
I'll go and watch it Oppenheimer I want
it's not that
interesting I didn't I didn't enjoy it
that much but it's not a bad movie it's
actually a good movie a reasonably good
movie maybe one of the best movies of
the year but not something you would
want to
rewatch okay Amisha says is all eyes on
Rafa is it a paid
tweet I promise you it's a paid tweet
it's not just a paid tweet it's a paid
real or paid Instagram story and paid
whatever else it's not just in Twitter
it's every it's in on other platforms as
well
uh so yes people are being paid for this
especially the so-called influencers you
know people with hundreds of thousands
of followers and all that they're being
paid to do this I know people who have
done that I personally know some people
who' have done that very
disappointing I cannot trust those
people
again uh so yes it's a paid it's a paid
thing it's a paid uh it's a paid uh
campaign or whatever you want to call it
my views in Bollywood tweeting about
this I have no issue with bolw TW
tweeting about this because that doesn't
surprise me that is something you would
expect them to do they've been doing
this for a long
time yeah we know that Bollywood is like
that no surprise there my my issue is
with the
so-called Nationalist influencers and so
on who have been tweeting about this and
posting this on Instagram that's that's
what uh kind of disappointed me
significantly okay
uh Shanay Verma says apart from jet
engine technology and this floating
nuclear plant technology being offered
by Russia what are some areas that where
India can develop its own research
massively without support everything
develop artillery develop machine guns
develop uh truck engines car
engines develop
drones various kinds of
drones high altitude long endurance hail
d d drones medium altitude long
endurance male drones develop loitering
Munitions develop suicide drones like
the the Shahed to that Iran has and
whatever else is available everywhere
else develop submarines of various kinds
develop a whole family of fighter jets
develop new missile boats there is so
develop robotic doggies that can carry
machine guns on their heads there's so
much India can and should develop
I could go on but yeah there's so much
India can do and should do and of course
it's not like we doing nothing that's
not true we have been we have been
testing all kinds of remarkably
remarkably interesting
longdistance weapons over the Indian
Ocean region there's there's a there's a
cruise missile that then deploys a
torpedo Under the Sea that's that's nice
I like it very creative and very scary
if you are on the opposition on the
opposing end of the thing yeah there's
good stuff India is doing but why not
Much More Much More Much More ai
ai where's the AI
anyhow SJ says can chimpanzees become
intelligent and become a threat to
humans
look every species has a certain upper
level of its intelligence now of course
if you genetically re-engineer
chimpanzee or put neuralink in its mind
or or or do whatever happened to Caesar
the in the Planet of the Apes Rise of
the Planet of the Apes in that case they
may become intelligent but that's
science fiction uh in a from a real
realistic perspective it's not likely to
happen any time in the next 5 to 10
years but eventually yeah if you use
neural link and you create super
intelligent chimps by implanting chips
and stuff into their brains then they
they could become a threat to humans
they
could
okay Tas says why was Egypt so important
in history for the Romans Persians and
other Empires but nowadays it has lost
its prominence in geopolitics you lose
power you lose all importance you lose
all relevance why was India completely
irrelevant for the past many since 1947
has anybody even bothered to talk about
India no was India relevant anywhere in
any great power discussion no India was
completely irrelevant it's only now that
India has becoming relevant in the past
10 years because India is now deploying
its power projection abilities in the
Indian Ocean Reg
India now matters India is now visible
in the Indian Ocean region and India is
is is a growing economy that also
matters what happened to Egypt Egypt got
smashed first it was smashed by the
Persians it was not smashed by the
Persians it was uh it was defeated by
the Persians and it came under Persian
occupation which allowed Alexander to
just walk in to Egypt and the Egyptians
welcomed him with with open arms as a
liberator but then he put his own
governor in place ineg Egypt and then
you had several generations of of Greek
rule in Egypt and once that was over
then you had Roman rule in Egypt Julius
Caesar conquered Rome uh sorry conquered
uh Egypt when tmy one of the tommies was
the was the was the king in Egypt and
then you had Roman rule in Egypt and
then you had Arabic rule in Egypt and
that was the end of Egyptian culture
civilization everything they don't even
speak the Egyptian language now anymore
so that's why Egypt completely
disappeared from all relevance today
Egypt is just an extension of the Arabic
world there's nothing Egyptian left
nothing of the original culture language
or anything that's left there and
politically it is powerless it is not
what where what's the power there's no
power there so once you lose power once
the you you lose that you become
irrelevant geopolitically so that is in
a nutshell what happened over the past
two and a half thousand years in Egypt
and that's why it is what it is
today all
right Yas Z says do we need to
genetically modify humans to effectively
explore
space well I'm not sure about that look
if you could I don't you don't need to
genetically modify humans let's say you
create an
exoskeleton a layer a layer outside your
skin skin let's say you create an EXO
seladon which is one atom Atomic length
thick just one Atomic layer and that
prevents the vacuum from affecting you
and then also maybe it has some
breathing you can attach a breathing
device to that something then you can go
into space without a space suit you wear
an invisible exoskeleton and you
completely safe and maybe it also
Shields you from the solar wind Cosmic R
and all that so you don't need to
genetically modify humans to do that but
obviously what I'm talking about is
completely science fiction but it's
technologically it's it's feasible it's
it's feasible according to the laws of
physics that's what I mean but
technologically it's a leap into the
unknown genetically modifying people is
is I think very dangerous because we
don't understand the genome properly
there's n what 90 95% per of the genome
is completely dark it's called the dark
matter of the DNA because we understand
nothing about it nothing at all but all
these components of your DNA they matter
they play some role otherwise they would
not exist nature is parsimonious it
won't carry unnecessary baggage and
replicate and pass it on so obviously it
plays some role we don't know what role
it is you start modifying genes it's
going to cause a disastrous chain
reaction because all these genes they
depend on each other and they have some
relationships and
connections and there are some genius
gen genius level scientists who say that
yeah we should we should have GMOs
genetically modified organisms that are
beneficial for Humanity because they
will give us plentyful crops and whatnot
but what about the the knockdown effects
27 Generations down the line which will
come which will become visible in in
seven years or 12 years what happens
then what about the knockdown effects
the 300 Generations down the line if
it's crops it's just what
century so you have to be really careful
about
when you when it comes to tampering with
nature tampering with with with your
genome you don't do that unless you
completely understand everything you're
doing right now we understand next to
nothing about what we're doing so we
shouldn't do
that
okay what
else okay Harel Agarwal says costs the
cost of books of icse is almost 10,000
rupees but for cbsc it's 2,000 Rupees
for Class 7 it's unfair also IC books
have nothing more great to offer they
are deliberately just made long
extensions of NC well I am not aware of
this but if it is true then yeah I think
you know truly speaking if everybody is
paying taxes then the government should
at least make education free and
Healthcare free in a civilized society
but obviously that's an idealistic
perspective but we had that in the past
in
India we even had had had that in
certain so-called princely States after
1947 for a short
while then everything became
commercialized so yeah I think it's
ridiculous I think there should be
standardization of
education and okay let's say you let's
say your textbooks cost money but then
it should not cost too much 10,000 bucks
for a bunch of worthless books nearly
worthless books doesn't make sense yeah
so there are so many problems in India's
education system it's rotten to the core
rotten
okay where are
we eyes on Rafa trending today can you
talk about that I spoke about it twice
already
sir I know you must have come in later I
get it you can rewind when this is over
and check it
out uh Shri balam Putin
sir why does a country of
Chile uh have that long and weird and
long shape let's take a look at that
Chile is in South America yes for fa so
this is the nation of Chile the capital
is Santiago why does it have this shape
I am not sure I think I had to read up
some history and then then get back to
you I don't know much about the history
of Chile there was a lot of instability
in South America Latin America after the
Napoleonic Wars and all these Governors
be they declared independence like
Bolivar Simon Bolivar and and whoever
else and all these people and that's how
all these nations were born I'm I'm just
giving you a very very rough and dirty
version of what happened obviously it's
a complicated process but uh so I don't
really know about the history of Chile
that much and how it acquired this
ridiculously long Chile like shape but
maybe I will read this up and get back
to you in in in a future live stream
right good question good question see
there are things I don't
know
uh okay what else we have Loop
ZZ says have you watched oppenheimer's
scene where he recites the Gita verses
verses they could have done it
differently what's your take yeah there
was a sex scene or something in which
he's there was some recitation of the
Gita or something the Bhagavad Gita I
don't know why what was the point of
that I just don't get it why do you have
to do it that
way yeah it was weird
strange didn't make sense was that
annoyed I don't care I don't care
doesn't make any difference to me
whether they're trying to offend me and
offend us I don't know what was the
purpose of that and what was the
intention behind this was it uh was it
done in order to offend
Hindus I don't know it was just strange
for
me
okay aaren says I watched the tashkin
files movies there's a mention of the
mokin AR volume 1 2 Etc K you be in the
world where there is about Congress Etc
can you elaborate this I have not read
the m in uh archive I have not read it
this but yeah the contents I'm kind of
aware of what is in there and it's not
surprising so I can't elaborate because
I've not read it I'm aware of it I'm
aware of the
Soviet influence let's say in India
obviously there would be influence every
powerful Nation wants to influence
everybody else through some way or the
other through Straight ways through
crooked ways and all so yeah of course
they did that uh the USSR but I haven't
read these books so I can't
elaborate
okay ADI Sharma says do you like the
breed German shepher I like to purchase
one should I go for it okay I'm going to
answer this straight I'm going to assume
that you're asking me a genuine question
question not the other German
Shepherd uh yeah it's it's a good dog
okay it's a it's somehow one of the most
popular breeds of dog but is it suited
to the Indian climate German shepher the
German shefer okay let's let's put the
German shepher on the screen shall we
let's go to Google so it's it's a it's a
very good breed of dog German
shefer uh spelling spelling bro so this
is the German Shepherd it's it's a great
dog it's used in the military it's used
in police forces very intelligent very
loyal very robust strong
Etc but as you can see this dog is a
furry dog so obviously it's evolved in a
climate where you had cold
weather as you can see it's very fur now
India the Indian subcontinent is a
mostly warm
place it's actually quite hot in in
summer much of India unless you go to
the north of India or the to the Far
East of India so it's a very warm place
India it's really hot actually in the
summer and do you want to subject a dog
an innocent dog to that sort of heat I
know people who have uh Siberian huskys
in
India a Siberian Husky can withstand
minus 20° Celsius temperatures and
you're subjecting that poor thing a poor
creature to 40° plus temperatures in
somewh in India why would you do that
isn't that
cruel so my point is when it comes to
India I would recommend that
you purchase or adopt an Indian breed of
dog a dog of an Indian breed so the
standard Indian dog I mean Indian
dog dog I mean the standard it's called
the paraya dog right
right this is the dog that suited for
India best suited it's got short fur
it's a mediumsized dog extremely
friendly dog extremely sociable dog
extremely intelligent extremely loyal
and very clean and almost an extremely
healthy no health issues no parasites
very very less likely to have parasites
as long as you take reasonably good care
of this dog and you have other dogs dogs
also indigenous dog bra
who all have short hair so that's what I
would recommend don't get any of these
long-haired dogs because they will end
up feeling tortured by the climate of
India get Indian
dogs you can have various indigenous
Indian dog breeds or you can go for the
standard issue Indian Pari dog extremely
good dog extremely good pet that's what
I would recommend German shefer and all
well it's it's a it's a prestig thing
right I have a foreign a dog of a
foreign breed cost me 7 lakh Rupees to
buy it or whatever it cost I don't know
I have no idea so why do that you like
dogs adopt Indian
dogs all
right
um Noob Clash of Clans says will India
and China fight a war in the future who
will win look it entirely depends on
China India is not going to start a war
with China but if the Chinese will start
a war India will to end the war I think
India will win the war as long as India
acts rapidly and takes Chinese territory
in Tibet rapidly and that's very
feasible China has a very thin presence
in Tibet like I said some time ago so I
think if we play our cards right India
will actually win this but the thing is
if you fight a defensive War India may
end up losing more than it gains and the
longer the war goes the more of an
advantage the Chinese will have so a
short sharp war on Chinese territory is
what India wants if Chinese start a war
okay then then make them pay a price
they will not forget and it's possible
India is not a is is no pushover I
assure you of
that Amisha Mishra says your seat
predictions for NDA and Indie are you
scared for 4th June look I don't know
much about Indian politics I mean I
don't follow it I don't know which seat
is where and what goes there and all I I
I observe and analyze intern
National geopolitics so I have no idea I
am I am not the right person to ask
about seed predictions and all that but
I am hopeful that that NDA will come
back to Power with a big majority am I
scared for fourth of June I'm kind of
worried but I hope my worries I'm always
worried look whenever there's an
election result I'm kind of
nervous and I'm nervous because if Mr
bod doesn't come back to Power it's the
end of the story for for India
essentially okay it's not the end of the
story India will continue to exist
continue to exist if Mr Modi doesn't win
but it will revert to mediocrity in the
damage that will be done in the next
five years is going to essentially end
any hope that India has of becoming
great again so that is why I'm kind of
worried just a little bit but I'm pretty
confident Mr Modi comes back to Power so
yeah shouldn't worry actually
technical technical an says is there any
scientific explanation for CH Chan JVS
how can a human live for so long okay
for a scientific explanation of
something I need a
sample right how does science work you
make an observation you replicate the
observation you collect
data and then you try to explain the
phenomenon so when you talk about any
phenomenon I need a sample I need mul
multiple samples I need observations I
need measurements I need
calculations and then based on the data
you formulate theories that is how
science works that is the scientific
method which originated out of India
India it is not some Western thing the
scientific method our scientists did
that used to do
it
now where can I find a sample of a
chinji so when you claim that a human
being lives this
long it's possible but I have not seen
the
evidence and in science you have to be
skeptical skepticism is the first rule
of
science okay that's just how it is you
don't like science then don't do science
but that's how science works there is no
place for belief or faith in
science there are so many scientists who
are religious people you know that who
believe in Rel have you seen the ISRO
Engineers doing the puas and all
that but if they use faith in building
the rocket imagine what outcome you'll
have my point is very simple in science
you don't have Fai there is no place for
Faith or belief there only what can be
observed and measured now show me a
chiranjivi I would like to have a sample
then I can talk about it and there's no
sample there are people who are alleged
to have been chinji well can I have a
person can I can I do a podcast with
with the
chiranjivi you need to have evidence
right I would like to do a podcast with
a chinji can you find me one you can't
so when you can't find such a person
then that thing doesn't exist from the
perspective of science because there is
no observational evidence so there you
go there's that's that's the
answer sahil Anand says howdy howdy bro
do you think interplanetary travel is
possible yeah it's possible of course
it's possible we already have the
technology it's just that it's it needs
to be tested properly rigorously uh
robustly we we have I mean not me I I
personally don't have a rocket but we
have the Space X uh Starship rocket that
is capable of taking humans to the Moon
it is still being tested and iterated it
is still still not human rated yet
because you know there may be certain
things that need to be refined and and
improved but yes by 2030 it could be in
in in position to take humans to Mars so
by the 2030s definitely 2040s you will
most likely have humans to Mars it's
definitely
possible definitely possible even ISO
can can send humans to Mars in a couple
of years I think the the the latest
rocket that ISRO has developed the lvm
whatever it is it is slightly more
powerful than the gslv whichever thing
it was and by using those weird not
weird but those long lengthy Maneuvers
orbit raising maneuvers you can send
humans to Mars I I wonder when isra will
develop a rocket that will take that can
take humans straight to Mars without
having to resort to orbit raising
Maneuvers but anyway so I think
interplanetary possible travel the
technology is almost there and it's
going to happen sooner or later by the
2030s for sure if not then then
definitely by the
24s so it is of course Very Much
possible very much possible we almost
there okay what
next okay shabri eloi says how does
gravity really work I mean the curvature
of space time Fabric and mass Bend space
is just an explanation but how does it
really Bend space look if I knew then I
would have a Noel priz
somewhere that's the best theory that we
have the best theory that we have so in
in in in 1900 just a 124 years ago the
best theory was Newtonian mechanics the
Newtonian view of gravity gravity as an
action at a distance
Force
okay so that was the newon in View and
then in 1905 Albert Einstein proposed he
he he came up with these five papers one
of which was the special theory of
relative ity and then 10 years later by
1915 he had put forth the general theory
of relativity and there is a theory that
has been tested rigorously and
extensively they have tried everything
they can to break the theory and to find
some flaws with it they've never found
any flaw it is the best theory that we
have when it comes to gravity general
relativity the presence of mass curves
or warps space time and the curvature of
space time tells Mass how to move and
it's not some some random ranting in in
words these are the Einstein field
equations that tell us what I'm saying
out in words it's
mathematics so uh that's what we have
that's the best theory that we have now
do we know how why does it happen then
you could also ask me why did the big
bang happen and that also we don't have
the answer to it there's so many things
we don't have answers to and that's why
physics is so
fascinating so yeah that's the best I
can tell you there are things we don't
know
and uh that's why physics is so
interesting and fascinating because
there is so much more to discover I mean
even general relativity has flaws it
throws up
Infinities in uh inside black holes for
example and that's obviously a problem
because Infinity is a division by zero
which means there is a flow in the
equations what's the flow we don't quite
know
yet
yeah
Rahul vodnala says can we see more
physics discoveries in the future like
it happened at the at its peak a century
ago so yeah the the Golden Age of
physics was in the first half of the
20th century when young men were doing
physics wner Heisenberg was in his early
20s when he discovered wave mechanics
and Then followed that up with the
discovery of the uncertainty principle
bohar was in his 20s when we came up
with the bohar model of the atom
Einstein was what 20 something 25 when
he published those five
papers uh POI was a young man when he
did all that work D was a young man when
he actually came up with quantum
mechanics to make sense of all these
jumbled experiments and observational
phenomena evidence on all that so it was
young men in their early 20s and mid 20s
who were doing all the work today if
you're a young man or young woman in
your mid
20s what work can you do in physics you
have to do your PhD you to do your post
doctorate then you to find a job
somewhere as as a I don't know assistant
or or assistant professor or reader and
then you you to publish or perish and
publish irrelevant articles year after
year after year where can you do the
work so right now because of the
terrible shape the academic system is in
it is designed to to prevent people from
doing any any meaningful research I'm
not talking about India I'm talking
about globally especially in the west it
is it is designed to prevent people from
doing meaningful
research and it is the the string theory
Mafia has a strangle hold on the physics
funding theoretical physics funding in
the US in the west so right now there's
going to be no golden ede of physics
right now maybe it can come out of India
if India gets its act it's act right and
and reforms the education system
especially the higher education system
and and makes it uh makes
it you know possible to do meaningful
research incentivizes meaningful
research but yeah right now there's no
ghou in age of physics coming up unless
somebody somewhere obscure outside of
the academic system can come up with
something like Einstein did in
1905 okay shahin Rahman zadan says the V
IC Crater of 536
CE uh which caused Great environmental
catastrophe around the world and played
a huge role in the politics of the 7th
Century CE my thoughts on such events
look such events are called black swor
events you never expect them you can't
predict them and they can spring out of
nowhere black swor events there are such
things that could erupt and and happen
anytime today a mega thrust earthquake I
mean we had one in the andman sea in
2004 right the the yeah 2004 imagine
that happens closer to land somewhere it
will devastate entire nations the
tsunami devastated Nations
volcano I mean you have a super volcano
sitting in the middle of the US in Utah
the Yellow Stone super volcano would you
like to see it I have actually been
there the Yellowstone super volcano uh
not this sorry let me put the map on the
screen
so there are all these uh things
incubating somewhere or the other and
yeah they could they
could unleash themselves at any time oh
sorry Yellow Stone is not in Utah where
is it it's in Indiana Montana ah let's
just Google it shall
we Yellow Stone National
Park ah
yes so this is National Park and it's
essentially a gigantic super volcano
hidden
under under the
ground Old Faithful yeah there's a big
geyser over here geizer geyser whatever
you want to call it and this guys are
erupts on schedule every 20 minutes or
whatever it is I don't remember right
now and so on so it looks like a nice
place it's it's a national park it's a
it's a tourist destination very popular
tourist destination for someone like me
who's interested in nature and all that
but it's a super volcano and the day
erupts it's going to change the future
the the the future course of humanity
there's the deck and traps of volcanism
that could happen again who knows there
are volcanos that have been dormant for
centuries that could erupt I mean the
last great volcano was I think Pino
wasn't it in 1991 in the
Philippines you have anak anak kakata
the son of kakata in the IND in in the
Indonesian Islands
you have Tambora I don't know what
Tambora is up to these days you have
there was Lake Tao in the the in New
Zealand as well so my point is these
events can happen anytime there's no way
to predict them and once they happen
they will change the the course of of
History so yes that that is something
that's beyond our control we can only
pray it doesn't happen another thing
that could happen is uh geomagnetic
storm the son I mean there was something
called what
event I forget the name of the event
which happened Century or two centuries
ago uh it was a tremendous geomagnetic
storm and if it happens today it will
fry all the satellites it'll kill off
the internet it will destroy electricity
grids around the world it'll send
Humanity set Humanity back a century or
so the damage it will cause will will
cost trillions of dollars to to
to repair and it could take decades to
before we get back on
track so yeah solar storms and all that
is is another such example of a of a
black storm Black Swan event it w cause
the kind of damage of volcano could
cause but it will it it'll
destroy electricity grids it'll destroy
internet connections it'll destroy
satellites on which everything depends
it'll send us back a century
so there's so much that can happen and
when one can only pray it doesn't happen
yeah Muhammad ismile says after
Independence what happened to the rulers
of the princely states the nawabs the
maharajas and so on well they were given
previe pures for some time for a few
decades uh so all these princely states
they were those kings and uh major Kings
minor Kings Etc nawabs and princes and
whatever
NS these people who were allowed by the
British to hold nominal power power in
name only in name okay they were only
puppets but they kind of assisted the
British in administration and helped the
British extract taxes and resources out
of India and all that they were entirely
puppets the true kings and queens of
India were all killed off in 1857 anyhow
these
puppet Kings princely States princes and
all after
1947 uh they had to merge with India
they did it voluntarily let's say all of
them most of them
voluntarily and they were given some
kind of income by the government of
India it's it was called a priv purse so
that kind of allowed them to maintain
their dignity and whatever estate little
estate the hair and all that and I think
that that was abolished in the 1970s by
prime minister Indira Gandhi and today
those people well they are common
citizens now
and most of them were were descendants
of of puppet Kings anyway so because all
the all the kings who fought the British
in 1857 they were defeated they were
killed off their families were destroyed
their lineages were destroyed and their
Crown was given to some far off distant
relation of theirs and those were
installed as the new Kings who were
puppets of the British or some of the
kings in 1857 chose not to fight the
British because it was too dangerous
but they still remained loyal to India
in some way or the
other and chose to compromise rather
than lose all power and lose all ability
to serve their people so somewhere of
that kind many were actually British
collaborators and so on and so forth but
after Independence they had a privie
purse for some for a few years for a few
decades in the 1970s sometime in the 70s
prime minister Indira Gandhi ended that
and today they are just common people
like everybody else
okay om B ker says how did Mesopotamia
disappear what happened to the culture
language and people okay what is
Mesopotamia let us go to Mesopotamia let
us get rid of Yellowstone shall we okay
we we remove that now we go to the
Middle East West Asia West Asia so we
are in the middle of Asia here and now
we go to West Asia let's go west of our
neighboring country
Persia and there we have Mesopotamia
which
is uh Syria and Iraq essentially now why
is it called Mesopotamia because it's
the it's the valley between two rivers
it's the valley between the Euphrates
and the
Tigris okay so look at this River look
at the city of Bagdad which river flows
through
Bagdad this is the tigis see tigis so
the tigis is the river that flows to B
Bagdad and there is another river called
the Euphrates and it is the river that
flows through
carala uh near carala sorry here it
is it's the
Euphrates and the narrow Valley between
these two rivers is
fertile as you can see it's kind of
greenish right so that is
Mesopotamia and this River I mean this
region has been historically very
significant you had so many
civilizations the Sumerians the acadians
the Assyrians and so on Etc who all
lived here who emerged out of this
region we used to trade with the
Mesopotamians we as in India in ancient
times during the sasat Sindu phase of
our history we used to trade with these
people we had good relations with them
uh they had great
dynasties and so on so they had Kings
like hamura like nabuk kraar nabuk
Kadar and so many more great dynasties
they had this uniform script that
emerged somewhere around 3,000 BC it was
even adopted by our Persian cousins
later on the hak shamish Dynasty and so
on so forth now what happened to the
Mesopotamians well first of all uh it
came under the sway of Pur during the
hakam dynasty the Ain
Dynasty um
Krush the great captured and conquered
the place um and freed the in freed the
Jews yes the Hebrew people uh from the
Yoke of the
Assyrians so that happened somewhere
around 500 BC or something around
roughly okay you can look up the dates
I'll give you the direction you follow
the direction so it came under the uh
rule of the
Persians then it was destroyed by
Alexander
when he conquered the region on his way
to destroying
Persia uh when when when when Dias the
third thirdd I think it was was in
power and
then uh eventually it came under the S
of Islam and there was it so long story
short disappeared just like Egypt did
disappeared
okay Mr Blue Wolf says I left a comment
on your video called what is space time
V Space and Time merg debating a claim
you made a while ago go check it out
when you all right all right I'll try
and find it Mr blue W 55 sure I'll try
and find
that
um okay J P FR says in Europe in the US
Christians committed witch burning of
women yes Salem witch burnings in the US
and Europe we all over the place yeah so
who practiced yeah the women who
practiced you could say ayurvedic
medicine and they the Christians
tortured women to death for having
ancient knowledge of the healing
Traditions that that's correct yes so um
before Christianity the the Europeans
used to practice their ancient culture
all across Europe you had a single
culture which manifested itself in a
variety of different ways the old Indo
European culture
and it is very closely related to the
Old Vic culture of India which was the
ancestral culture same thing in
different shapes and forms so one of the
things in the Indo European culture is
that women had a very prominent role in
society is opposed to the role that
women had in abrahamic society or still
have wherever abrahamic Society is
actually abrahamic properly like true to
the word of the
book so the old Indo-European Society
women
got a very prominent role in that and
their role yeah there were gender roles
like it or not
boohoo so their role was that of the
healers and the the custodian of the old
traditions of healing which is the well
you could call it the European version
of Aura
yeah and that made them very highly
respected regarded and it gave them a
certain amount of of power as well you
know when you
where let's say you were gathering honey
and you are you were mauled by a
bear that lady had power of life or
death over you she could save your life
or or if she did not do well you would
die so that's the kind of power women
had
so the in the a sorry in the abrahamic
worldview women are second class
citizens so but European Society of the
old age of the old days before uh
Christianity revered women
so that had to be broken down so
obviously you the the church declared
that any woman who has any specialized
old knowledge is a
witch is a witch and she communes with
the devil
apparently
so any
knowledge was made punishable by death
any extra knowledge any extra ability
out of the ordinary out if the only
woman who was accept acceptable was a
completely
illiterate and helpless woman and any
woman who had any other qualities was
branded of witch and tortured to death
burned to death drowned to death pressed
by stones to death various kinds of
death death Death
yeah uh and uh I don't know hundreds of
thousands of women at a conservative
estimate were burned alive in Europe
maybe millions of them and you also had
the Salem witch burnings in North
America that also was that sort of thing
so
yes pretty dark
history a man with no name is a good
movie yes it's a Trilogy okay man with
no name says Western historians
propagate that Alexander when he
conquered Persia he adopted their
culture and the people of Persia showed
no resistance to him and welcomed him do
you think it's true the people of Persia
fought Alexander okay uh dasas fought
Alexander there were two major battles
one the first battle between dasas II
and Alexander was somewhere in in
present day
Syria I forget the name of the place and
Alexander was able to defeat dasas the
third he was able to capture dias's wife
and
children and he treated them very well
do you know why he treated them very
well the's wife and children he treated
them very well because they were a
prestigious set of captives
the more you the better you treat them
and the more respect you give them the
more
valuable a possession they become of
yours I captured the wife and family of
the emperor of
Persia so the more respect he gave them
the better he treated them the more his
Prestige as a conqueror
grew okay so that's why he treated
there's wife and and and mother
and and children so
well eventually I believe his wife died
there his wife died and uh or mother
died I think the wife died if I'm not
mistaken if I remember correctly uh so
there was the first battle then
Alexander goes on a detour he goes and
besieges the City of Ty in the Eastern
Mediterranean eventually he takes the
city and crucifies tens of thousands of
people alive to death just for fun then
he goes and takes over Egypt then he
goes further into Persia and there's a
battle called The Battle of gamea in
which dasos faces his second defeat
massive defeat and eventually dasas has
to run away and eventually he's betrayed
by his own people and he's
killed and Alexander took Babylon he
took everything he found lots of gold
you know the the treasury of the
Persians he shipped it all off to his
mother in Macedonia he impoverished
Persia yeah but he was a very well
behaved person at times so this is the
truth Alexander was a robber on a
colossal
scale he was cruel beyond measure he
crucified tens of thousands of people
alive he burned entire Villages alive on
when he was trying to invade India in in
Western India in in present day syn
balistan maybe Punjab
okay Barbarian absolute Barbarian so
that's the truth of
Alexander a robber on a vast scale
colossal
scale what up says thoughts on the T20
Cricket World Cup being hosted in the US
any
predictions uh well okay it's good to
make this thing this this this sport
popular in the US all right I have no
issue with that predictions I don't know
who's doing what uh um India should do
well I mean India has the IPL everybody
gets to play everybody practices
everybody has match practice tremendous
match practice India should do well but
India typically doesn't do well in World
Cups Indian players perform at their
best in the IPL but in the World Cup
what happens what happens to the
so-called greats the last time India won
the World Cup T20 was 2007 the inaugural
World Cup when dony went with a
completely young and inexperienced team
right and I remember the the last shot
of the of the final the missar shot the
scoop and that was the last ball that
jindra Sharma bowled in his entire
International career and he got the
Wicket that won the World Cup for India
2007 since then India has not won a
single T20 World Cup as far as I can
recall and 2011 we won the World Cup
with all the old guys who retired maaf
pel Sachin
dulhar Zahir Khan I don't know who else
yeah so so my point is you you want to
win World Cups you have to be
ruthless uh you cannot be sentimental
even if you have senior players who are
no longer doing great even if they're
doing good but not great
out behave like the Australians look
what they did to Steve Steve war look
look how they treated Dean Jones you
know people say that I have recency bias
I remember what they did to Dean Jones
at the age of what 30 32 he was retired
he was tied permanently he still was
playing do domestic he was at the peak
of his prowess but they sidelined him
Dean Jones Alan Alan B I think retired
at the right time Steve W wanted to play
more but they put him to pasture and in
India the great players get to decide
when they
retire so this this culture that you
have in India this non ruthless culture
it is not suitable for winning World
Cups so so I think India has enough
talent to to have five teams that can
win the World Cup but the one team that
matters I don't know I don't know who's
been selected or not I'm sure it could
have been a better team but anyway so
these days I don't watch cricket much
it's a timec consuming Affair watching
Cricket I have not watched the single
game of the IPL this
season I believe uh Kolkata won the IPL
the the last last time I had a live
stream that IPL final was on anyway yeah
I hope India wins this world cup but I
don't know can't make predictions
because I've not been following Cricket
that
much rishit Agera says what's the
contrast between the UN World happiness
index and the global happiness index by
Chinese news Outlet India ranks second
on that leaving the G7 behind countries
behind well I was not aware of this the
Chinese also have one well why don't we
have one Global happiness index uh so
the Chinese are saying India is second
in that really who's first China
look I don't know I'm not aware of this
Global Chinese Happiness index but these
happiness indexes are subjective how do
you measure the level of happiness that
a person has okay you can ask people to
self-report Happ your level of Happiness
from 1 to 10 10 means you the peak of
your happiness one means you are at zero
happiness that is a self-reporting thing
people don't always self-report honestly
and accurately and how large is a sample
200 people 2,000 people you think you
can garge a country's happiness levels
based on a 2,000 person survey when the
country is 1.4 billion people so all
these things are very subjective and
they they don't really make much
difference and much of it is just
propaganda and narrative setting okay
that's how I see
it
okay were you able to impress girls in
your younger days if yes then how look
you want to impress girls be yourself
that's
it if you want to impress someone don't
be interested in impressing anyone why
do you want to impress anyone be
yourself be the best version of yourself
and live your life and try to impress
yourself ask yourself every day am I
proud of what I have done thus far and
have I done something today that I can
be proud
of okay don't be concerned with other
people's opinions
and other people's you know views about
you if you have that attitude you will
impress everybody including girls that's
what I would
say Okay shanj Varma says I will be
pursuing MSC in artificial intelligence
soon from the UK awesome
great uh how should I approach
interacting with Indian government
Indian official organizations for
improving the state of research in India
look right now you're going to go and
study your for your for your msse so
right now I would recommend that don't
worry
about the process of improving the state
of research in India right now your sole
focus should be on you getting your
degree and in the
process mastering the subject that is
your first object that should be your
first objective right now don't worry
about other
things right now don't worry about
improving the state of research here or
there or anywhere
else focus on mastering the subject and
acquiring your degree once that is
achieved focus on the next 10 years of
your career make a name for yourself
make a reputation for yourself get
acquire as many skills as possible in
the field of artificial intelligence
acquire as much experience as possible
in the field of artificial intelligence
and acquire as much wealth as possible
personal wealth then when you are 30 35
or whatever or maybe earlier if you're
if you're really good and when you have
a sufficient amount of
wealth and a reputation to go with it
then you'll be in a position to interact
with people who matter and you'll be in
a position to actually make a difference
as a student you can't make a difference
okay so you have to be
realistic and you need to have a
step-by-step approach that's what I
would
recommend and life is long and there's a
lot you can do but you have to approach
it
realistically as a student who's who's
not started the MSC there's nothing you
can do to improve the state of research
in
India it's only when you reach a certain
stage in your life that you can
influence things positively so all the
best
and uh yeah I wish you the greatest of
success okay Samar achara says why did
the US Outsource its manufacturing it's
because of the
uh minimum wages laws in the US so in a
nation like the US I'm just saying
hypothetically okay let's say in the
1960s the minimum wage was let's say
let's say I don't know what it was okay
I'm just saying let's say it was $10 an
hour so if you have a worker who works
in a factory and works in an8 hour shift
you have to pay that guy $80 for that
for that eight hour shift that he works
that's a minimum wage but if it's a
highly skilled person you may have to
pay him five times that so instead of
$80 you may have to pay him five $400
okay
now you Outsource that to a poor third
world nation like China and the
1970s instead of paying an $8 per hour
minimum wage you had to pay 10
cents minimum wage in China let's say
imagine how much money you can save by
Outsourcing your stuff to China it's
simple economics it's tremendous profit
you can make by doing this so you
Outsource all your work to a third world
country and in the process you turn it
into a manufacturing
superpower that's what happened
right
um uh where what what what else what
else what else what
else okay uh AAR man says what are your
opinions about the kivu issue was the
agreement with Sri Lanka Justified is
very controversial topic you asked me
about yes okay let's go to map
okay where are we yes
subcontinent so we have this island
between India and Sri Lanka in the park
state which is called kachu which one is
it where is it we have to locate it is
it
this
kachu and there's a church well
wonderful so this
island belonged to India and at some
point in time in the' 70s or whenever it
was was I don't remember the government
of India gifted it to Sri Lanka gifted
just like at some point in time the
government of India under the great
magnificent Mr javal Neu gifted the Koko
Islands to
Burma uh which what is this prep Paris
yeah coko islands this one here we just
gifted it to Burma because it was the pr
Minister's family possession right it
was his private property apparently so
something like that happened in the 197
s this island kivu was just gifted to
Sri Lanka and then what happened later
in the 2000s 2010s is that when Indian
fishermen would venture in this region
for fishing the Sri Lankan Navy would
would open fire on them and shoot them
some of them I don't know if they died
many of them were were were were
arrested and jailed in Sri
Lanka because now Sri Lanka has official
sovereignty over this island which IND
gifted for no reason so that's the deal
I think I think we should not be gifting
Islands or any land any territory to
anybody no prime minister has the right
to do that whoever it is because these
territories are not their personal
property it belongs to the nation and
the people of India it's our ancestral
heritage you just can't gift it because
you felt like it uh but yeah that's what
had used to happen in India in the past
which is uh which is very
unfortunate Mohammad ismile says where
is the coor today I think the coor is on
the is part of the crown jewels of the
British king so uh that lady what's her
name Elizabeth Liz who died Charles's
mother she had a crown and the kohinur
was the largest gemstone the largest
diamond on her on her crown and now that
she has uh passed on the crown I would
expect has uh come into her son's
possession who's now the king of England
and the kohinur is on that
Crown so yeah and uh very interesting
story that kohinur has it used to be one
of the eyes of uh of a morti of Lord
Vishnu in a temple somewhere in India
then it was the property of Maharaja
Ranjit Singh and then the British stole
it
and and yeah it is right now stolen
property it belongs in India it's an
Indian Stone mined in India qued in
India but now part of the stolen wealth
that the British have so that's the
that's where it is today the
kinor okay geopolitical du says why is
the problem problem of baldness
increasing I was not aware of an
increase in baldness is it
so what is what is the cause of baldness
I think it's excess testosterone that is
the cause of baldness not sure what it
it is but uh yeah this is something new
for me I was not aware that there's an
epidemic of
baldness yeah so I don't know I don't I
don't have the answer to that right now
I'll look it
up
um Tanish Kumar says will artificial
intelligence improve or worsen
employment and work conditions look it's
going to take a whole lot of uh
professions out of the mix okay it's
going to it's going to make lots of
things obsolete lots of people in
certain professions will lose their jobs
uh research assistant no one needs
research assistance today h have chat
GPD do all the donkey work for you you
pay what whatever it is um so
so so research research assistance will
become irrelevant and obsolete uh proof
readers will become obsolete fact
Checkers will become obsolete uh data
entry jobs will become obsolete there's
so many jobs which will become
completely Obsolete and some new jobs
will also be
created um AI ethics jobs and whatever
so a bunch of jobs will become Obsolete
and a bunch of jobs will be created but
I think more jobs will become obsolete
than jobs new jobs being created and
when you bring robotics into the mix
into the
picture then lots of uh blue color jobs
will become obsolete because robots will
be able to do everything very soon and
when you take Robotics and you take Ai
and you merge them together that's a
game changer so yeah it's it's going to
actually worsen employment especially
when it comes to uh employment in
lowincome Nations where you have lots of
unskilled labor like manual labor and
all that that's going to become obsolete
rapidly
okay anuda day says what are they doing
inside Area 51 do you think they have
UFOs in there so let's go to Area 51
shall we uh where is it it's in the US
somewhere is it in
Arizona is it in Arizona let us see Area
51 area 50 it's in Nevada it's in Nevada
okay where is
Nevada it's somewhere here okay Area 51
Nevada
and this is a dry lake
bed okay so you zoom
out and you can see where it
is it's a dry lake bed and you can see
that uh they have these runways and all
that if you see the length of the runway
let's see the length of the
runway 5.68 kilometers and it can be
extended even more so let's say it's
between the main Runway is about 3
kilomet the extended one is about 5 and
a half kilm and the even more extended
one is about 7 or 8 kilomet that is like
proper test Runway and there are
multiple runways and there are all these
buildings whose nature is unknown
there's this weird Pond or something
over
here and yeah so what is this it is
alleged by some people that there are
UFOs and aliens in here maybe it's a
hotel for aliens and parking space
garage for UFOs well these don't look
like UFOs to be but obviously if there
are UFOs they'll be hidden so what do I
think it is I think this is a place
where they should test futuristic
aircraft like the SR71 FSR whatever one
Blackbird and right now and I'm sure the
in the past the stealth
bombers B2 B21 whatever else was tested
here so I think it's a place where they
design develop and test futuristic
aircraft classified aircraft I
personally do not think they have aliens
and UFOs there but obviously I don't
know because I've not been there so
maybe they do have aliens and UFOs there
but it is more likely it's just a secret
testing
facility all right that's what I
think ah Miguel Diaz says why was Sudan
partitioned I think there was a Civil
War and Sudan was in a PL in in a state
of chaos and then you had darur South
Sudan all that um
yeah it's it's a long complicated
matter basically Civil War situation
lawlessness Anarchy no no real
government and then Nations just break
apart like that
uh yeah something like that happened I
don't remember exactly what the sequence
and chronology was but today you have
South Sudan and there's the darur issue
also happening there and obviously there
are other foreign powers involved in
this who want to exploit the
circumstances for their benefit it so
overall to give you a very very
rudimentary answer Civil War Anarchy
Sudan Somalia it's always been the past
few decades a place with almost zero
government no functioning government no
functioning Services delivery no
functioning anything even Somalia for
the longest time I mean in the 70s they
had such nice uh it was a nice country
compared to what it is today and then in
the '90s you had you know Muhammad Farah
ID those War so-called War Lords who
were fighting the Americans obviously
they'll fight the Americans foreigners
but so on so yeah and today you have
almost no governance in Sudan in Somalia
Somalia I'm talking about uh piracy the
most lucrative business is piracy you
become a pirate but then you get
captured by proper navies and all that's
the thing uh so Sudan wasn't partition
it kind of broke apart that's what
happened okay okay Kiran bandagi Kiran
bandagi
says your view on unidentified submerged
objects you're talking about crypto
zoology are you crypto zoology hey it
was fascinating to me as a kid uh
Lochness Monster you know where Lochness
is let's let's let's take a look at
Lochness I haven't seen that for a while
on the map so it's an
Ireland so the Irish word lock means
Lake and where is loes a Wonder this is
lo no it's in Scotland is it
loes in Irish we say l l u g so is it in
Scotland
Loess this is
lo okay let's just Google it I mean
let's just search for it instead of
going through Lake after
Lake
lockness ah wasn't far I wasn't far so
this is Lochness where there's supposed
to be a prehistoric monster that looks
under the water it's a pretty deep
lake and yeah you don't really get to
see the Monster here no matter how far
you zoom in but this is the location of
Lochness which is rumored to have a
gigantic
uh uh mososaurus or some some form of
ancient dinosaur or something apparently
that's what the pictures look like the
alleged pictures look like but you don't
know and then there's
the the the deep ocean where who knows
what creatures lurk the deep ocean is
gigantic we haven't even explode 5% 10%
of it under the water under sea so who
knows what could lurk down there there
could be Krakens and there could be
gigantic dinosaurs some people say um
and so on so it's a fascinating topic as
a kid I was really fascinated with this
crypto
zoology and I know people very reliable
people who have seen
things you know see creatures that that
don't that aren't classified or or seen
anywhere
else yeah
so it's interesting my view is that
there could be something out there or
there could be many things out there
that we not aware of because the ocean
is so huge and it is so underexplored so
it's possible there could be creatures
species of creatures species species of
animals and and marine animals Etc that
could uh exist that we are not aware of
maybe large ones maybe maybe the Meg is
out there the Megalodon the
ginormous shark which makes the white
shark great white shark look like a kid
like a toddler maybe but we don't know
so I think it's
fascinating okay Nan Roshan says what is
kalpa vigraham what do you think about
it I don't know what it is I hear this
question all the the time people ask me
all the time what is the kulpa vraa I
think it's some
some some copper or some metallic statue
of some kind of
God and some people claim it is 30,000
years old or something listen how do you
know it's 30,000 year old 30,000 years
old or whatever age it is you cannot
carbon date metal metal is metal it's
not carbon there's no carbon in metal so
how do you claim it is so and so years
old maybe it is but what's the evidence
that that's my point so I've heard of
this thing called kalpa vigraham or
something and they say it's an it's very
old well I haven't researched it because
people make claims about a metallic
object the date you can't date a
metallic object you can't carbon date it
it's like people say that this Stone was
carbon dated to so and so years you
can't carbon date stone it is a mineral
it's not organic material and neither is
is is uh metal
so yeah I don't really know much about
it I've not bothered to look into it
because it makes no sense to me
obviously I could be wrong there are so
many things that I could be wrong about
but come
on AEL says where the persons Indians
are the other way
around I call the persans or cousins
look you go back to the rigc times same
people same people you have the Ric
Clans so many Clans the Alina Clan
the uh parwa Clan which is the originat
which is the origin of the Persians and
then they lost the battle of the this
this is pre pre Ric time I'm talking
about the Battle of the 10 Kings which
happened before the event of the before
the Ric times that's the oldest battle
we know about and it's it's mentioned in
the
Riga and one of the Clans that was
defeated was the parwa clan and the
parwa went westwards because they were
Fe then they to go into Exile what's
west of India Baba it's Persia their
Capital was parur
persis so you go back several thousand
years Persians were Indians Indians were
Persians okay that is the
chronology all
right oh ainka indar says what's your
thoughts on the MH370 plane found in
Cambodia through Google Maps I was not
aware of it I have Google Maps here but
I think it'll take me years to find it
so yeah I was not aware of this is it if
it has been proven it would be all over
the news but it hasn't come all over the
news so maybe somebody has made a claim
based on something they found in Google
Maps uh is it the MH 370 we don't know
so I I personally haven't seen this
claim I wasn't aware of this but I'll
check it out always good to find these
suggestions and and Snippets of news in
the Q&A
okay okay Vishnu says I'm 29 I want to
get UI ux design job is it a good idea
well I don't know I don't why do I not
know because I don't know your skill set
I don't know your experience I don't
know your background so I don't know if
it's right if it's right for you or not
if you are an experienced programmer
with some a few years of experience in
this or at least if you have knowledge
of this then it may make sense but if
you are a complete
beginner let's say hypothetically I
don't know but let's say a person is a
beginner is it a good idea to start in
this if you are talented and you can
learn very fast and improve fast and
produce the results then it may still
make sense and so on and also it the
other question is how much uh of a bank
account do you have I mean you need to
have something in your bank account that
will sustain you for a few months while
you start a new job or you start hunting
for a job so your financial situation
also matters if you are not financially
very very well off then maybe you should
stick to a more safe job until you get a
healthy bank balance and then you can
search for something so it's there's so
many factors that that go into this so I
can't really tell you without knowing
you personally properly yeah so
yeah all
right the just says will the USA ever
dare to invade Russia or China or India
look you don't need to invade countries
if you can simply control the world
through power projection in the in the
financial system the US it owns the
world's Reserve currency it doesn't need
to invade Nations it can make Nations do
whatever it want it wants just through
the control it has over the US dollar uh
but when it comes to Russia the US won't
dare to inv invade Russia not as long as
Putin is in power and not as long as the
the Russians have more nukes than the US
the Russians are a great defensive power
they're not a great offensive power they
have no almost no power projection
capabilities in the oceans but they have
the scariest nuclear Arsenal Arsenal in
the world which is why the US will not
dare invade Russia somebody asked the US
why did you invade Iraq they'll say we
invaded Iraq because they had
wmds then then why don't you ask them
why don't you invade Russia they'll say
are you crazy they have
wmds so the truth is Iraq had no wmds
and that's why they invaded Iraq under
the pretext of chasing those wmds but
they know Russia actually has wmds
weapons of mass destruction and that's
why they want they won't invade Russia
China well if they invade China it'll
destroy the Chinese economy which will
destroy the US
economy in India India is a big Market
that the Americans want to tap into why
invade India so an invasion needs to be
a logical process it needs to have a
genuine reason a strategically sound
reason you don't invade because you feel
like because you don't like someone you
don't invade a nation because you don't
like them because an invasion is an
expensive process it's costly you will
lose time you will lose material you
will lose men women will become widows
you will have to bear the brunt economic
brunt of all that and only if your
Invasion can give you way more than what
you lose that's when the Eon The
Invasion makes sense logically and
obviously it should not make you a Pari
the world should not boycott you because
you did something very bad and evil
invading an innocent nation and so on so
yeah there you have it okay I think we
are well past two hours so I'm going to
end this live stream here thank you so
much once again for all your questions
and lots of people are still asking I'm
so sorry to those of you those questions
I could not take today but we're going
to keep on doing this every week so I'll
see you very soon in the next live
stream in which I'm going to take
questions from the comments all right
the next one is on Friday and then on
Saturday so thank you so much once again
for the questions and I'll see you very
soon and don't forget to to keep on
raising your status thank you very much
see you soon bye